Let's focus on just one country variable,
先侧重于一个国家变量
such as the USA country variable and see how
例如变量 country_usa
we can estimate the values that will plug into the risk model.
看看如何估算将代入风险模型中的值
For the factor exposure matrix and its transpose,
对于因子暴露度矩阵及其转置矩阵
we want each stock's factor exposure to the USA country factor.
我们需要获得每支股票对 country_usa 因子的暴露度
This can be set to one,
如果公司在美国
if the company is based in the USA and zero if it's based in another country.
则设为 1 如果在其他国家 则设为 0
You could also imagine choosing decimal values between zero and one
还可以选择一个 0-1 之间的小数
based on how much of the company's revenue is generated in the USA.
表示公司有多少收入是在美国产生的
In any case, the point is that we can estimate the values for the factor exposures.
总之 我们可以估算因子暴露度的值
Next, we want to fill in the co-variance matrix of factor returns.
接下来 我们需要填充因子收益率协方差矩阵
So, we want to obtain a time series of factor returns.
所以需要获得因子收益率时间序列
To make it easier to follow,
为了简单起见
I'm going to simplify our model so that it contains only one factor.
我将模型简化为只包含一个因子
So, the factor co-variance matrix contains
所以因子协方差矩阵
just a single variants for the factor return of country USA.
只包含一个 country_usa 因子收益率方差
Also, the matrix of factor exposures has just one column for the single factor.
此外 因子暴露度矩阵只有一列 表示一个因子
The number of rows equals the number of stocks.
行数等于股票数量
We want to get the factor return,
我们想要获得 country_usa 的
time series of the country USA,
因子收益率时间序列
so that we can calculate a variance from it.
从而根据它计算方差
The journey to estimating a time series starts with a single step.
估算时间序列首先从单个时间步开始
So, lets first estimate the factor return for a single time period.
我们先估算一个时段的因子收益率
Once we estimate the factor return for one time period,
估算一个时段的因子收益率后
we can repeat the process to estimate factor returns for more time periods.
我们可以重复地估算更多时段的因子收益率
Okay. We're going to estimate the factor return for a single day.
Ok我们将估算一天的因子收益率
So, we take a cross section by collecting data points
我们将获取横截面数据
for a single day but across multiple stocks.
即收集多支股票一天的数据点
Each stock has a factor exposure associated with it.
每支股票都有关联的因子暴露度
The factor exposure is one,
如果公司完全暴露于 country_usa
if the company is 100 percent exposed to country USA.
则因子暴露度是 1
The factor exposure is zero,
如果股票完全没有暴露于 country_usa
if the stock is completely not exposed to the country USA.
则因子暴露度是 0
It's somewhere in between,
中间值表示
if the stock is partly exposed to USA,
股票部分暴露于美国
but also to other countries.
部分暴露于其他国家
We'll also have the return for each stock on that time period.
我们还需要获得每支股票在此时段的收益率
So, given the stock return and factor exposure,
所以给定股票收益率和因子暴露度
we want to estimate the factor return.
我们想要估算因子收益率
We have several data points,
我们有多个数据点
one for each stock in the stock universe.
股票池中的每支股票一个数据点
So, we can use a regression model to fit a line through
我们可以使用一个回归模型
the plot of stock return versus factor exposure betas.
在股票收益率与因子暴露度 β 形成的图表中画一条线
The slope of that line is the estimate for the factor return for that one time period.
这条线的斜率等于该时段的估算因子收益率
We can interpret this estimate of factor return as the amount of return that can
我们可以将此因子收益率估算值解释为
be attributed to being exposed to the risk factor of country USA.
可以由暴露于风险因子 country_usa 来解释的收益率部分
So, that was one factor return for
这就是使用一个横截面数据
a single time period using a single cross-section of data.
得出的一个时段的一个因子收益率
Yeah. We've now estimated one point.
耶我们估算出一个数据点了
Remember that we want to find factor returns over time.
我们希望计算随时间推移的因子收益率
If we repeat this cross-sectional regression for multiple time periods,
如果我们针对多个时段重复这种横截面回归流程
we'd get a time series for the factor return.
将获得因子收益率的时间序列
That's great. If we calculate the variance of the factor return time series,
太好了如果我们计算出因子收益率时间序列的方差
we can plug it into the co-variance matrix of factor returns.
可以将其代入因子收益率协方差矩阵中